William S. Rosecrans Papers
William S. Rosecrans Papers,
- Framed etching of General Rosecrans, Added January, 1982.
Holloway, William R.(Letter to) Box 48, folder 117
Hood, John B. (Mention of) Box 10, folder 130
Hooker, Joseph (Letters from) Box 10, folder 173
Box 19, folder 6
Box 57, folder 76A
Hooker, Joseph (Mention of) Box 8, folders 52, 133
Box 9, folder 57
Box 34, folder 89
Box 55, folder 106
Box 57, folder 18
Houston & Great Northern Railroad Company Box 23, folder 106
Howard, Oliver O. (Mention of) Box 8, folder 133
Howard, Volney E. (Letter to) Box 50, folder 3
Howe, Timothy O. (Letter to) Box 52, folder 3
Hubbard, Gardiner G. (Letter from) Box 18, folder 9
Hughes, John J. Box 8, folder 50
Humphreys, Andrew A. (Letter from) Box 27, folder 60
Box 30, folder 58
Box 31, folders 41-42
Humphreys, Andrew A. (Letters to) Box 48, folder 18
Hunt, Alexander C. (Letter from) Box 26, folder 61
Hunt, Alexander C. (Letters to) Box 51, folders 1, 2
Hunt, Washington (Letter from) Box 2, folder 152
Hunt, William H. (Letter from) Box 52, folder 3
Hunter, David (1802-1886) (Mention of) Box 8, folder 52
Hunter, William (1805-1886) (Letters from) Box 10, folder 101
Box 12, folder 13
Huntington, Collis P. (Letters from) Box 17, folders 144-145
Box 18, folder 125
Box 19, folders 129, 155
Huntington, Collis P.(Letters to) Box 50, folder 2 (4 letters)
Huntington, Collis P. (Mention of) Box 17, folder 46
Box 19, folder 29
Box 26, folders 67, 93
Box 27, folder 29
Box 33, folder 94
Box 55, folders 69, 70, 76, 79
Box 61, folders 23, 43, 53, 56
Box 68, folder 5
Hurlbut, Stephen A. (Letters from) Box 7, folders 117-118
Box 8, folders 118-119
Hurlbut, Stephen A. (Mention of) Box 7, folders 39, 74-75, 77, 84, 86-88, 102, 116, 126
Box 8, folder 135
Box 68, folder 46
Hyde, Henry B. (Letter from) Box 26, folder 145
Ingersoll, Charles J. (Mention of) Box 78, folder 93
Interoceanic Railroad Concession (Mexico) Box 23, folders 2, 4, 6, 106
Boxes 24-28, passim
Box 47, folders 89-139, passim
Box 48, folders 1-15, passim
Boxes 90-91
Interoceanic Railroad Concession (Mexico) see also: Union Contract Company of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia
Inyo County, California (Earthquake in) Box 55, folder 98A
Iowa (Farming in Washington County, Iowa) Box 65, folders 1-70
Iowa (Railroad lines in) Box 2, folders 83, 93-94
Irish in the U.S. (Promotion of communities of) Box 36, folders 46, 52
Iuka, Battle of, 1862 Box 11, folder 27
Box 40, folder 113
Box 44, folders 23-41
Box 48, folder 30
Box 56, folder 35
Box 59, folders 55-56
Box 62, folders 16, 35
Box 81, folder 31
Jackson, William H. (Mention of) Box 10, folder 138
Jamestown, Tuolumne County, California (Mining in) Box 60, folder 46
Box 71, folders 31-40
Box 77, folders 34-40
Jaquess, James F. (Mention of) Box 8, folders 40A, 42, 61A
Box 9, folder 148
Jefferson, Thomas (Mention of) Box 78, folder 98
Jesuits in the U.S. Box 2, folders 44, 46, 80
Box 4, folder 2
Johnson, Andrew (Documents signed by) Box 124, folders 11, 13
Johnson, Andrew (Letters to) Box 47, folder 35
Box 49, folder 5 (2 letters)
Box 53, folder 56
Johnson, Andrew (Mention of) Box 9, folder 1
Box 10, folder 180
Box 11, folder 30
Box 12, folders 57, 85
Box 53, folder 103
Box 60, folders 6, 32
Box 66, folder 62
Box 71, folder 7
Box 76, folder 21
Johnson, Reverdy (Mention of) Box 67, folder 62
Johnson, Richard W. (Letter from) Box 8, folder 64
Johnson, Robert U. Box 48, folder 131
Johnston, Joseph E. (Mention of) Box 8, folders 58, 94, 96, 118
Jones, Frank J. Box 43, folder 26
Jones, John P. (Letters from) Box 28, folder 50
Jones, John P.(Letters to) Box 51, folder 3 (2 letters)
Jones, John P. (Mention of) Box 27, folder 111
Box 117, folder 31
Jones, William P. (Letter from) Box 8, folder 91
Joyce, John A. (Manuscript poem by) Box 81, folder 37
Juarez, Benito Pablo (Letters from) Box 16, folder 41
Box 17, folders 40, 103
Box 21, folder 135
Box 22, folder 108
Juarez, Benito Pablo (Letters to) Box 47, folders 57, 78, 92, 102-103
Box 49, folder 6 (4 letters)
Box 50, folders 1 (3 letters), 2, 3 (5 letters)
Box 51, folder 2 (2ltrs.)
Juarez, Benito Pablo (Mention of) Box 12, folder 130, 142-143
Box 17, folder 131
Box 20, folders 80, 123
Box 21, folders 13, 66
Box 22, folders 12, 26, 69
Box 27, folder 87
Box 55, folders 116, 118
Box 62, folder 127
Julian, George W. (Letters from) Box 117, folder 39
Box 36, folders 46, 52
Julian, George W. (Mention of) Box 47, folder 29
Kanawha River, West Virginia (Improvements in navigation of) Box 4, folder 63
Box 6, folders 21, 90
Box 10, folder 43
Kansas & Pacific Railroad Company Box 12, folders 69, 111
Box 15, folder 2
Box 17, folders 5, 53
Box 18, folder 62
Box 19, folders 46, 84, 102
Box 20, folders 71, 95
Box 22, folder 53
Box 117, folder 68
Box 68, folder 5
Box 96, folder 8
Kautz, August V. (Letters from) Box 14, folder 16A
Box 39, folder 119
Box 40, folder 58
Kearny, Philip (Mention of) Box 12, folder 141
Box 58, folder 36
Keifer, Joseph W. Box 81, folder 15
Kellogg, Francis W. (Letter from) Box 8, folder 98
Kellogg, William P. (Letter from) Box 27, folder 43
Kelly, James E. (Letter from) Box 35, folder 121
Kelton, John C. (Letters from) Box 11, folder 45
Box 41, folders 2, 38
Kemper, Jackson (Letter from) Box 1, folder 50
Kenesaw Mountain, Battle of, 1864 Box 38, folder 129A
Kenyon College, Gambier, Ohio Box 65, folders 89-121
Box 66, folder 1-7
Keyes, Erasmus D. (Letters from) Box 35, folder 30
Box 36, folder 89
Keyes, Winfield S. (Letters from) Box 21, folders 82, 107
Box 28, folder 124
Box 29, folders 8, 28, 33
Keyes, Winfield S. (Letter to) Box 50, folder 3
Kimball, Nathan (Letter from) Box 15, folder 104
King, Clarence (1842-1901) (Mention of) Box 21, folder 40
King, George A. (Letter from) Box 43, folder 90
King, George G. (Letter from) Box 2, folder 113
Kirby-Smith, Edmund (Mention of) Box 3, folder 71
Box 10, folder 39
Kirk, Edward N. (1828-1863) (Mention of) Box 7, folder 148
Kirk wood, Samuel J. (Letter from) Box 7, folder 138
Know-Nothing Party See American (“Know-Nothing”) Party
Kurtz, John D. (Letters from) Box 1, folder 91
Box 2, folders 37, 90A, 147, 149
Box 3, folders 51, 61, 76-77, 90, 101-102, 107, 115, 119, 123, 134
Laetare Medal Box 104
Box 124, folder 20
La Habra, California Box 11, folder 75
Lander, Frederick W. (Mention of) Box 10, folder 87
Larrabee, Charles H. (Letters from) Box 9, folder 66
Box 11, folders 42, 53, 56, 59, 73-79, 81, 83, 87-88, 90-92, 94, 96, 98-100, 102-104, 106-107, 109, 112-117, 130
Box 12, folders 4, 22, 74
Box 15, folders 7, 47, 122, 145
Box 16, folder 9
Box 18, folders 94, 129
Box 19, folder 20
Box 22, folder 29
Box 28, folder 118
Box 31, folder 141
Box 37, folder 32
Box 53, folder 137
Box 54, folder 7
Larrabee, Charles H.(Letters to) Box 49, folder 5 (22 letters)
Box 50, folders 1 (2 letters), 3
Box 54, folder 11
Larrabee, Charles H. (Mention of) Box 20, folder 107
Box 26, folder 93
Box 27, passim
Box 74, folder 33
Latham, Milton S. (Mention of) Box 12, folder 16
Lawton, Alexander R. (Mention of) Box 1, folder 52
Le Duc, William G. (Letter from) Box 42, folder 75
Lee, Robert E. (Letters from) Box 2, folder 46B
Box 12, folders 32, 36, 54
Lee, Robert E.(Letters to) Box 47, folder 49
Lee, Robert E. (Mention of) Box 8, folder 120
Box 12, folders 50, 55
Box 61, folder 11
Box 66, folder 107
Box 87, folders 1-2
Le Fevre, Benjamin (Letters from) Box 16, folder 2
Box 17, folder 165
Box 18, folders 2, 21, 29-30, 34, 38
Lefferts, John (Letters from) Box 78, folders 88-99, 121
Legouais, Thomas (Letters from) Box 2, folders 14, 23, 33A
Lerdo de Tejada, Sebastian (Letters from) Box 12, folder 130A
Box 14, folders 71, 88, 92, 94A, 102-103, 105
Box 22, folder 113-114
Box 24, folder 79
Box 28, folder 86
Box 53, folder 110
Lerdo de Tejada, Sebastian (Letters to) Box 49, folder 5, 6
Box 51, folders 1, 2 (2 letters), 3 (4 letters), 4
Lerdo de Tejada, Sebastian (Mention of) Box 14, folders 56, 114, 121
Box 27, folders 52, 8794, 104, 114-115, 131, 161, 165
Box 30, folder 130
Box 31, folders 84, 117, 84, 109
Box 63, folder 39
Box 70, folder 100
Lewis, William B. (Letters from) Box 1, folders 18, 22, 25
Lexington (U.S. Ship) Box 1, folder 67
Lincoln, Abraham Box 124, folders 6-7
Lincoln, Abraham (Letters from) Box 8, folders 35A, 40A, 45A, 103A, 113A, 126-127, 129, 133, 138
Box 9, folders 17, 122
Box 10, folders 6-7, 10, 19, 38, 44, 58
Lincoln, Abraham(Letters to) Box 45, folder 96
Box 45, folder 96
Box 46, folders 27, 52-53, 62, 83, 104, 109-111
Box 47, folder 30
Box 48, folder 111
Box 49, folder 2 (5 letters)
Lincoln, Abraham (Mention of) Box 7, folders 62, 149
Box 8, folder 16
Box 9, folders 44, 148, 155
Box 10, folders 22, 24, 46, 126
Box 12, folder 53
Box 19, folder 151
Box 117, folder 117
Box 42, folder 133
Box 53, folder 103
Box 62, folder 72
Box 66, folders 61, 115
Box 86, folder 9
Lincoln, Robert Todd (Letters to) Box 48, folder 112
Box 52, folder 3 (4 letters)
Lincoln, Robert Todd (Mention of) Box 53, folder 103
Logan, John A. (Mention of) Box 14, folder 18
Box 61, folder 68A
Longstreet, James (Letter from) Box 12, folder 61A
Longstreet, James (Mention of) Box 9, folder 20
Box 80, folder 25
Lookout Mountain, Battle of, 1863 Box 34, folder 89
Loras, Jean M.P. (Mention of) Box 2, folder 75
Los Angeles & Independence Railroad Company Box 30, folders 5, 31
Louisiana Military Institute, Alexandria Box 7, folders 13, 17
Louisville & Nashville Railroad Company Box 8, folder 92
Luers, John H. (Letter from) Box 5, folder 128
Luttrell, John K. (Letter from) Box 52, folder 1
McAllister, Julian (Letters from) Box 27, folder 158
Box 33, folders 66, 97
McArthur, John (1826-1906) (Letters from) Box 7, folders 80, 110, 122
McArthur, John (1826-1906)(Letter to) Box 44, folder 135
McArthur, John (1826-1906) (Mention of) Box 7, folders 71, 76
McCabe, James D. (Letter to) Box 48, folder 110
McClellan, George B. (Letters from) Box 7, folder 53
Box 53, folder 19
McClellan, George B. (Mention of) Box 2, folders 7, 157
Box 7, folders 52, 140
Box 8, folders 11, 52
Box 9, folders 116-117
Box 10, folder 4
Box 22, folder 28
Box 36, folder 50
Box 59, folders 6, 9, 32, 42-43
Box 66, folders 61, 63
Box 76, folder 78
McClellan Minute Men Box 10, folder 21
McClelland, Robert (Letter from) Box 53, folder 6
McCook, Alexander M. (Letters from) Box 8, folder 155
Box 12, folder 75A
Box 36, folder 63
McCook, Alexander M. (Letters to) Box 48, folder 36
Box 51, folder 1
McCook, Alexander M. (Mention of) Box 9, folder 72
Box 69, folder 29
McCook, Anson G. (Mention of) Box 38, folder 129A
McCook, Daniel (1834-1864) (Letter from) Box 8, folder 16
McCook, John J. (1845-1911) (Letter from) Box 17, folder 78
McCook, Robert L. (Letter from) Box 7, folder 58
McCulloch, Ben (Mention of) Box 7, folder 155
McCulloch, Hugh(Letters to) Box 49, folder 5 (2 letters)
McDowell, Irvin (Letter to) Box 48, folder 113
McDowell, Irvin (Mention of) Box 8, folder 36A
Box 17, folder 17
Box 48, folder 112
Box 59, folder 3
Box 60, folder 75
McElroy, John (Letter from) Box 2, folder 48
McKean, Thomas J. (Letters from) Box 7, folders 76, 105
Box 53, folders 26, 32, 36-38, 45-46
McKean, Thomas J.(Letters to) Box 44, folders 121, 125, 136-137
Box 45, folders 74, 105
McKean, Thomas J. (Mention of) Box 7, folders 91, 93-94, 104
McKinley, William (Letter from) Box 78, folder 27A
McKinley, William (Letter to) Box 54, folder 84
McMaster, James A. (Letters from) Box 2, folder 39
Box 3, folder 17
Box 5, folder 126
McPherson, James B. (Letters from) Box 7, folders 90-91, 115, 119-120, 127, 133
McPherson, James B. (Letters to) Box 44, folder 136
Box 45, folder 30
McPherson, James B. (Mention of) Box 7, folders 104, 106-109, 131A
Box 21, folder 98
Box 82, folder 2
McRuer, Donald C. (Mention of) Box 26, folder 67
Mad River & Lake Erie Railroad Company Box 4, folder 98A
Mahan, Dennis H. (Letters from) Box 3, folders 132-133
Mahan, Dennis H. (Letter to) Box 44, folder 8
Manningsville Mining Company, New York Box 7, folders 8, 12, 14
Mansfield, Edward D. (Letters from) Box 9, folder 117
Box 12, folder 96
Mansfield, Joseph K.F. (Letters from) Box 2, folders 24, 52A-53, 124
Mansfield, Joseph K.F. (Mention of) Box 3, folder 67
Box 59, folder 2
Marcy, William L. (Mention of) Box 3, folder 110
Box 5, folder 134A
Mare Island Navy Yard, San Francisco Box 40, folder 77
Mariscal, Ignacio (Letters from) Box 14, folder 53
Box 15, folders 85, 114
Box 16, folder 105
Marshall, William R. (Letter from) Box 10, folder 135
Marshall, William R.(Letter to) Box 47, folder 28
Martin, John A. (Letters from) Box 18, folders 99, 130
Mason, Charles (1804-1882) (Letters from) Box 4, folders 7, 69-70, 76-78, 87-88, 90, 96, 98-99, 105, 110, 112-113, 125
Box 5, folders 25, 48, 50, 59, 77, 82, 85-86, 100, 152, 156
Box 6, folders 24, 35, 43
Mason, Charles (1804-1882) (Letters to) Box 49, folder 1 (30 letters)
Mason, James L. (Letters from) Box 2, folder 154
Box 3, folders 13, 25
Mason, James L.(Letters to) Box 44, folder 9
Mason, James L. (Mention of) Box 3, folder 60
Matthews, Stanley (Letters from) Box 32, folders 61, 120, 128, 140
Maximilian, Emperor of Mexico (Documents signed by) Box 124, folder 12 (3 documents)
Maynard, Horace (Letter from) Box 24, folder 40
Medellin Railroad Company Box 14, folder 37
Meigs, Montgomery C. (Letter from) Box 43, folder 83
Meigs, Montgomery C.(Letters to) Box 45, folder 136
Box 46, folders 9, 22
Meigs, Montgomery C. (Mention of) Box 2, folder 154
Box 3, folder 26
Box 59, folder 96
Memphis Pacific & El Paso Railroad Company Box 15, folders 15, 77
Box 16, folders 46, 63
Box 17, folder 92
Box 19, folders 114, 117, 160
Box 21, folder 8, 42, 78
Box 24, folder 80
Box 25, folder 60
Box 61, folder 22
Box 68, folders 4-5, 23, 32, 96
Merrill, William E. (Letters from) Box 10, folder 33
Merrill, William E. (Letters to) Box 49, folder 5
Mexican Claims, 1870 Box 61, folder 21
Mexican War, 1845-1848 Box 1, folders 68, 70, 82, 84, 88, 92
Box 5, folder 29
Box 65, folders 12-13, 79-85
Mexico (Economic development of) Boxes 14-20
Box 89, folders 6, 9, 14-15, 17-22
Box 90
Mexico (Mining in) Boxes 17-23
Box 93
Mexico (National Bank of, proposals for its establishment) Box 14
Box 25, folder 128
Box 47, folders 78-79
Box 89, folders 1-4
Mexico (Railway projects in) Boxes 12-18
Boxes 90-92
Mexico (Rosecrans as U.S. Minister to) Boxes 12-14
Box 89, folders 5, 12
Military Order of the Loyal Legion of Honor of the U.S., California Commandery Box 82, folder 6
Millard, Harrison (Letter from) Box 21, folder 97
Miller, John F. (Letters from) Box 30, folders 86A, 118
Box 31, folders 96, 129
Miller, John F. (Letters to) Box 48, folder 38
Box 49, folder 6
Box 51, folder 4 (3 letters)
Box 52, folders 1 (2 letters), 3
Milton, Homer V. (Mention of) Box 78, folder 89
Missionary Ridge, Battle of, 1863 Box 10, folder 4
Box 86, folder 4
Missouri (Description of a trip to, in 1818) Box 78, folders 100-111
Missouri (Politics in, 1864) Boxes 9-10
Missouri Pacific Railroad Company (Versus the U.S. in claim for damage to its road during the Civil War) Box 31, folder 151
Box 117, folder 2
Box 32, folder 92
Box 81, folder 13
Mitchell, John H. (Letter from) Box 117, folder 52
Mitchell, Robert B. (Letters from) Box 8, folder 77
Box 9, folders 41, 47-48
Mitchell, Robert B. (Letter to) Box 52, folder 3
Montgomery, Zachariah (Printed pamphlet by) Box 87, folder 18
Moorhead, James K. (Mention of) Box 10, folder 22
Morgan, George W. (Letters from) Box 14, folders 95, 122
Morgan, George W. (Mention of) Box 59, folder 46
Morgan, Philip H. (Letter from) Box 42, folder 8
Mormons Box 21, folder 63
Mormons (Colony of John D. Young on the Little Colorado River) Box 37, folder 122A
Mormons (Polygamy question in 1881) Box 87, folder 19A
Morrill, Justin S. (Letter from) Box 43, folder 72
Morrill, Justin S. (Letter to) Box 48, folder 124
Morse, Ephraim W. (Letters from) Box 11, folders 47,50,61-62,72,93, 111
Box 12, folder 76
Box 14, folders 28, 33
Box 15, folders 15,64
Box 20, folders 68, 110, 117
Box 21, folders 11, 74, 132
Morse, Ephraim W. (Letters to) Box 49, folder 5 (3 letters)
Box 50, folders 1, 3
Morris, Gouverneur (Mention of) Box 78, folder 98
Morton, Oliver P.(Letters to) Box 46, folder 25
Box 47, folder 73
Morton, Oliver P. (Mention of) Box 59, folder 109
Mount Vernon Silver Mining Company, New York Box 10, folder 183
Box 11, folders 33, 84
Box 47, folder 70
Box 49, folders 3-5
Box 60, folders 12, 26, 28-29, 32, 36A-37, 45, 47, 50-51, 53, 59
Box 61, folder 13
Box 64, folder 58
Box 66, folders 116,118
Box 71, folders 9,30
Mower, Joseph A. (Letters to) Box 44, folders 25, 76
Mowry, Sylvester (Letters from) Box 15, folder 160A
Box 16, folders 46, 64-65, 77, 80, 82, 86, 94, 159
Box 17, folders 99, 153
Box 18, folders 149-150
Mowry, Sylvester (Letter to) Box 49, folder 6
Mulatos Mine, Sonora, Mexico Boxes 33-36
Box 37, folder 10
Box 53, folder 107
Box 54, folders 42-43
Box 93, folders 1-6
Murfreesboro, Battle of, 1862-1863 Box 8, folders 40A, 45A, 61A
Box 17, folder 7
Box 37, folder 31
Box 59, folders 70, 72-73
Box 69, folder 26
Box 76, folders 17, 98A
Box 80, folders 17-18, 21-22
Box 82, folders 14-16
Box 86, folder 4
Negley, James S. (Letters from) Box 8, folder 68
Box 19, folder 148
Box 25, folders 42, 131
Box 26, folder 100
Box 27, folder 92
Box 43, folder 19
Negley, James S. (Letters to) Box 50, folder 1
Box 51, folders 2,3
Negley, James S. (Mention of) Box 9, folders 57, 72
Box 19, folders 7, 39, 66, 137
Negro troops in the Civil War (Recruitment of) Box 8, folders 104, 107, 109-111
Box 9, folder 122
Box 10, folder 75
Nelson, Thomas H. (Letters from) Box 14, folder 82
Box 19, folders 3, 11
Nelson, Thomas H. (Letters to) Box 47, folders 58 139
Box 49, folder 6
Box 50, folder 3 (2 letters)
Box 51, folders 2, 3 (2 letters)
Nelson, Thomas H. (Mention of) Box 14, folders 42, 45, 55, 61, 70, 72, 117
Box 15, folder 29
Box 21, folder 144
Box 67, folder 68
Nevin, William W. (Letters from) Box 25, folders 67, 70, 117
Box 26, folders 78, 92, 107, 150
Box 27, folders 13, 33, 141, 182
Box 28, folder 41
New Bedford Harbor, Massachusetts (Survey of, 1853) Box 3, folders 4-5, 19, 23, 34
New Mexico (Road surveys in, 1848) Box 2, folder 38
New Orleans (Cholera epidemic at, 1848) Box 2, folder 40
New York Tribune (Cholera epidemic at, 1848) Box 9, folders 10, 36-37
New York Tribune (Tribute to Rosecrans) Box 11, folder 44
Newton, John (1823-1895) (Letters from) Box 1, folders 56, 80, 85, 88, 93, 101, 114A
Box 3, folders 63, 66, 74
Box 117, folder 78
Box 35, folder 13
Box 54, folder 52
Box 69, folder 87
Newton, John (1823-1895) (Manuscript by) Box 95, folder 11
Newton, John (1823-1895) (Mention of) Box 1, folders 74A, 106
Newton, Robert S. (Letter to) Box 53, folder 105
Nicholls, Francis R.T. (Letter to) Box 52, folder 1
Northern Pacific Railroad Box 35, folder 114
Nicholson, John P. (Letters from) Box 29, folders 90, 104
Box 30, folders 62, 117
Nicolay, John G. (Letter to) Box 48, folder 135
North Pacific Coast Railroad Box 29, folder 108
Northwestern Gas & Water Pipe Company, Bay City, Michigan Box 21, folders 47, 71, 91
Notre Dame, University of Box 71, folders 2-7
Box 77, folders 12-16, 53
Box 124, folder 20
Noyes, Edward F. (Letter from) Box 33, folder 73
Ogden, William B. (Letter from) Box 19, folder 82
Oglesby, Richard J. (Letter from) Box 32, folder 143
Ohio River (Legislation for improvement of, 1856) Box 6, folder 97
Oliver, John M. (Letter to) Box 44, folder 112
Oliver, John M. (Mention of) Box 7, folder 76
Oliver, Paul A. (Letter from) Box 53, folder 102
Olmsted, Frederick Law (Mention of) Box 8, folders 37, 40
Opdyke, George (Letters to) Box 50, folders 1, 2
Ord, Edward O.C. (Letter from) Box 3, folder 27
Ord, Edward O.C. (Mention of) Box 5, folder 134A
Box 7, folders 83, 87-88, 102
Box 40, folder 113
Box 45, folder 4
Box 59, folders 43, 55
Oregon (Indian wars) Box 5, folder 148
Oregon (Settlement of) Box 1, folders 71, 75
Oregonian, Portland, Oregon (On Rosecrans' campaigns in 1863) Box 9, folder 38
Oroville & Virginia City Railroad Box 14, folders 4, 16
Orth, Godlove S. (Letter to) Box 50, folder 2
Orth, Godlove S. (Mention of) Box 10, folder 22
Orton, William (Letter from) Box 21, folder 143
Orton, William (Letter to) Box 50, folder 3
Otis, George A. (Mention of) Box 7, folder 43
Otis, Harrison Gray (Letters from) Box 32, folders 118, 147, 157
Box 78, folders 27, 29
Overland Monthly, San Francisco (Financial crisis of, in 1875) Box 31, folders 23, 38
Packer, Asa (Letter to) Box 49, folder 6
Pacific Mail Steamship Company Box 4, folder 30
Box 14, folder 22
Pacific Railroad Survey Box 17, passim
Palmer, Innis N. (Letter from) Box 12, folder 83
Palmer, Innis N. (Mention of) Box 43, folder 133
Palmer, John M. (Letter from) Box 8, folder 69
Palmer, William J. (Letters from) Box 11, folders 52, 69
Box 21, folders 32,43,101, 116-117, 122, 127, 139, 141
Box 22, folders 15, 24, 32
Box 23, folders 21, 26-27, 32A, 96-97
Box 24, folders 1, 89, 96
Box 25, folders 30, 33, 43, 47, 51, 66, 73-77, 83-84, 88-89, 91
Box 26, folders 6, 35, 39, 45, 47, 54, 64, 75, 79, 87, 94, 101, 109-110, 127, 135
Box 27, folders 7, 52, 98, 117
Box 28, folder 111
Box 29, folder 19
Box 39, folder 68
Box 54, folder 5A
Palmer, William J. (Letters to) Box 25, folder 67
Box 47, folders 42-43, 46, 111, 118, 125
Box 48, folder 9
Box 50, folder 3 (5 letters)
Box 51, folders 1 (49 letters), 3 (90 letters), 4 (2 letters)
Box 53, folder 145
Palmer, William J. (Manuscript by) Box 90, folder 6
Palmer, William J. (Document signed by) Box 90, folder 32
Palmer, William J. (Mention of) Box 22, folders 45, 53, 77
Box 25, folders 60, 63, 71, 139
Box 26, folders 12, 34
Box 27, folders 47, 54, 138, 155, 171
Box 53, folder 145
Box 61, folders 73, 76, 78-79, 83, 85
Box 70, folder 99
Parke, John G. (Letter from) Box 17, folder 14
Parkhurst, John G. (Letter from) Box 43, folder 3
Parrott, Robert P. (Letter from) Box 1, folder 89
Parrott Gun Box 7, folder 29
Parsons, John E. (Letter from) Box 17, folder 61
Paulding, Hiram (Letters to) Box 44, folders 15-16
Paulist Fathers Box 35, folder 113
Box 60, folders 68-69
Box 63, folders 5-32, 71
Box 77, folders 49-63
“Paw Paw Question” in Missouri, 1864 Box 9, folder 99
Box 59, folder 114
Payno, Manuel (1810-1894) Box 16, folders 29, 125
Box 25, folder 94
Box 26, folder 38
Peck, William G. (Letter from) Box 31, folder 8
Pemberton, John C. (Mention of) Box 59, folder 59
Pendleton, George H. (Letters to) Box 48, folder 115
Pendleton, George H. (Mention of) Box 66, folder 121
Perkins, George C. (Letters from) Box 78, folders 19-20
Perkins, George C. (Document signed by) Box 87, folder 11
Perry, Alexander J. (Letters from) Box 16, folders 108, 171
Phelan, James D. (Letter from) Box 78, folder 24
Phelps, Charles H. (Letter from) Box 41, folder 31
Philadelphia Centennial Exhibition, 1876 (Mexican participation in) Box 25, folder 67
Phillips, Wendell (Letter to) Box 48, folder 116
Piatt, Donn (Letters from) Box 9, folder 128
Box 10, folders 153, 166
Piatt, Donn (Mention of) Box 66, folders 64, 70, 100
Pico, Andres (Mention of) Box 77, folder 58
Pierce, Franklin (Document signed by) Box 124, folder 3
Pierpont, Francis H. (Letter from) Box 8, folder 128
Pillow, Gideon J. (Letter from) Box 12, folder 58
Pittsburg Landing, Battle of, 1862 (See Shiloh, Battle of, 1862)
Pleasonton, Alfred (Letter to) Box 49, folder 2
Plumb, Edgar L. (Letter from) Box 22, folder 22
Plumb, Edgar L. (Mention of) Box 12, folder 10
Box 23, folders 23, 36, 78, 82
Box 24, folders 39, 77, 86, 99, 109
Box 25, folders 9, 15, 29
Box 26, folders 105, 108, 124, 160
Box 27, folders 49, 82, 114- 115, 120, 131, 145, 161, 165
Box 117, folder 10
Box 32, folder 5
Box 68, folder 42
Box 70, folder 99
Box 90, folder 21
Poe, Orlando M. (Letter from) Box 34, folder 14
Polk, Lucius E. (Letter from) Box 43, folder 41
Polk, Sarah (Childress) (Letters from) Box 7, folder 143
Box 8, folder 49
Pope, John (Mention of) Box 7, folder 39
Box 8, folder 36A
Box 59, folders 37, 39-40
Popocatepetl, Mount, Mexico (Ascent of) Box 2, folder 8
Porter, Fitz-John (Letters from) Box 37, folders 110, 112